<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Diversify Project on Vivek Nallur</title>
    <link>http://viveknallur.github.io/tags/diversify-project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Diversify Project on Vivek Nallur</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Copyright &amp;#169; by Vivek Nallur</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://viveknallur.github.io/tags/diversify-project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Algorithmic Diversity</title>
      <link>http://viveknallur.github.io/diversify/algorithmic-diversity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://viveknallur.github.io/diversify/algorithmic-diversity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Algorithmic diversity aims to quantify the amount of natural diversity available in a pool of algorithms, and their effect on system properties.  In many domains,
there are multiple algorithms available that can perform the same / similar tasks. For example, there are a plethora of algorithms available for sorting, load-balancing,
compression, etc. Almost every computer science student studies multiple sorting algorithms, and their respective complexity (big-O). Apart from complexity, there are
many aspects in which algorithms differ, data structures, strategies, etc. These aspects have an impact on the real-world performance of software systems. In most
cases, the developer or system administrator tries to foresee the operating environment of the software system, its input characteristics and chose the best / optimal
algorithm, that they could possibly implement. However, in the real world, operating environments rarely stay stagnant and the desired quality attributes of the system
do not stay at the same level, as when deployed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are investigating whether using a pool of algorithms, instead of a single optimal pre-chosen algorithm, could impact the software system&amp;rsquo;s quality attributes
in a positive way, and if so, how do we quantify it? And herein lies the challenge. A little reflection would lead us to the conclusion that, in an uncertain
operating environment, using a pool of algorithms would definitely affect the system&amp;rsquo;s robustness, but by how much? And can we pre-determine the
amount of diversity in this pool? These are some of the questions that we aim to answer, with our experiments in algorithmic diversity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Diversify Project</title>
      <link>http://viveknallur.github.io/diversify/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://viveknallur.github.io/diversify/introduction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://diversify-project.eu/&#34;&gt;Diversify&lt;/a&gt; is an EU FP7 project, that aims at
leveraging diversity, to improve software systems.  An inter-disciplinary
effort, one of our partners is the ECOBIO&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:2767292a573dc549b9b4297b701af3ab:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:2767292a573dc549b9b4297b701af3ab:1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; group
 from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.univ-rennes1.fr/english/&#34;&gt;Université de Rennes 1&lt;/a&gt;. The
intent is that knowledge, concepts, and techniques flow in a two-way stream,
between ecology and computer science. The full list of partners is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.inria.fr/en/centre/rennes&#34;&gt;INRIA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sintef.no/home/&#34;&gt;SINTEF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tcd.ie/&#34;&gt;TCD&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.univ-rennes1.fr/english/&#34;&gt;Université de Rennes 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TCD works, along with INRIA and SINTEF, to automatically insert diversity into software. There are several levels at which a software system can be characterized:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Source code level&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Algorithmic level&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Architectural level&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ecosystem level (one piece of software in relation to others)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At each of these levels, our perspectives and concerns are different, and so are the basic units that can be manipulated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2767292a573dc549b9b4297b701af3ab:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ecobio.univ-rennes1.fr/dernieres_publications.php&#34;&gt;http://ecobio.univ-rennes1.fr/dernieres_publications.php&lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:2767292a573dc549b9b4297b701af3ab:1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>